<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  
  <!-- EN: starjack -->
  <Starjack.label>ستارجاك</Starjack.label>
  <!-- EN: Engineered for life among the stars, starjack are built to withstand the unforgiving conditions of deep space living. Their reflective pressure-adaptive skin provides insulation against extreme temperatures and allows them to survive brief exposure to hard vacuum. These adaptations make them invaluable for spacewalk repairs and emergency decompression scenarios.\n\nMost starjack spend their lives beyond planetary gravity, leading to lower muscle mass and reduced physical strength compared to baseline humans. However, their resilience in zero-gravity environments makes them essential for maintaining orbital platforms and working aboard long-haul vessels.\n\nAs one of humanity’s oldest xenotypes, starjack played a crucial role in the colonization of space. They are a common sight on deep-space stations and interstellar ships, where genetic modification is often a more cost-effective solution than upgrading spacecraft to support unaltered human physiology. -->
  <Starjack.description>مصممون للحياة بين النجوم، الستارجاك مبنيون لتحمل الظروف القاسية للعيش في الفضاء السحيق. جلدهم العاكس المتكيف مع الضغط يوفر عزلاً ضد درجات الحرارة القصوى ويسمح لهم بالنجاة من التعرض القصير للفراغ القاسي. هذه التكيفات تجعلهم لا يقدرون بثمن لإصلاحات السير في الفضاء وسيناريوهات تخفيف الضغط الطارئة.\n\nيقضي معظم الستارجاك حياتهم خارج الجاذبية الكوكبية، مما يؤدي إلى كتلة عضلية أقل وقوة بدنية منخفضة مقارنة بالبشر الأساسيين. ومع ذلك، فإن مرونتهم في بيئات انعدام الجاذبية تجعلهم أساسيين لصيانة المنصات المدارية والعمل على متن السفن الطويلة المدى.\n\nباعتبارهم أحد أقدم الأنماط الغريبة للبشرية، لعب الستارجاك دوراً حاسماً في استعمار الفضاء. إنهم مشهد شائع في محطات الفضاء السحيق والسفن بين النجوم، حيث يكون التعديل الجيني غالباً حلاً أكثر فعالية من حيث التكلفة من ترقية المركبات الفضائية لدعم الفسيولوجيا البشرية غير المعدلة.</Starjack.description>
  <!-- EN: Engineered for life among the stars, starjack are built to withstand the unforgiving conditions of deep space living. Their reflective pressure-adaptive skin provides insulation against extreme temperatures and allows them to survive brief exposure to hard vacuum. -->
  <Starjack.descriptionShort>مصممون للحياة بين النجوم، الستارجاك مبنيون لتحمل الظروف القاسية للعيش في الفضاء السحيق. جلدهم العاكس المتكيف مع الضغط يوفر عزلاً ضد درجات الحرارة القصوى ويسمح لهم بالنجاة من التعرض القصير للفراغ القاسي.</Starjack.descriptionShort>
  
</LanguageData>